<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Generated by Squarespace V5 Site Server v5.13.594-SNAPSHOT-1 (http://www.squarespace.com) on Thu, 28 Oct 2021 18:04:35 GMT--><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Rimple on Tech</title><link>http://rimple.com/tech/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 12:54:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><copyright></copyright><language>en-US</language><generator>Squarespace V5 Site Server v5.13.594-SNAPSHOT-1 (http://www.squarespace.com)</generator><item><title>I AM NOT A RECRUITER</title><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 12:50:11 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2019/6/11/i-am-not-a-recruiter.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:36192062</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I just received some disturbing news from someone scammed for an employment opportunity. The scammer used my name (Ken Rimple) and said I worked for Spectrum Jobs as a recruiter. They did an interview with the candidate and then tried to coerce them to purchase equipment, then send them a check.</p>

<p>News flash, scam scum: I do not work for anyone other than my employer of over 10 years, Chariot Solutions, and I am certainly not a recruiter. I do participate in interviews, from the technical side, once we vet a candidate enough to move into the technical interview stages. But I do not represent any employment agency.</p>

<p>If you find yourself chatting with some "Ken Rimple" on a messenger app with some fake interview process, it is not me. If you are contacted by my employer, Chariot Solutions, and they move to a technical interview, it IS me. Our website is <a target="_blank" href="https://chariotsolutions.com">chariotsolutions.com</a> and you can use the Contact Us form to reach our recruiting and sales staff to make sure your call is legit.</p>

<p>And finally, identity theft is a crime. Expect anyone using my name illegally to be targeted by law enforcement.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-36192062.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Governor Wolf's Tech Services Tax Resumption - Bad for IT</title><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 13:23:31 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2017/5/19/governor-wolfs-tech-services-tax-resumption-bad-for-it.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:35913129</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Governor Tom Wolf has a rotten idea in his new budget plan...</p>

<p>Last month he came to the Philly Tech Week event at Temple University, talked to a bevy of attendees and then spoke at a keynote. He made sure to show up for a <a href="https://twitter.com/RimpleOnTech/status/859927314485915649" target="_blank">photo opportunity in my training session</a>, and talked with the majority of the students. He also addressed the community in a keynote. With that level of engagement, you'd think he was there to learn more about the tech community and <em>support</em> it.</p>

<p>You'd be wrong. Governor Wolf, who is a Democrat in an heavily Republican state government, just released his budget outline. Either he works for Don King (TAKE A <span class="caps">DIVE</span>!) or he's incredibly tone deaf.</p>

<h2>A State Technology Services Tax</h2>

<p>Ok, Governor Wolf. You picked a bad time to try to destroy a vibrant industry. Have you looked around lately? All. You. Have. To. Do. Is. Stay. In. Office.  Trump, a complete idiot with zero experience, interest and aptitude in governing the country, is going to implode soon. So why would you <span class="caps">BOTHER </span>to present a budget that targets a single industry and tries to kill it with a heavy tax. </p>

<p>For those of you who don't know, the Wolf budget plan <a href="http://www.phillymag.com/business/2017/05/16/philadelphia-tech-tax-wolf-budget-proposal/" target="_blank">suggests a services tax be restored on the tech industry</a>, and though his would only be the fifth state to enact it, his would be the largest, at 6%.  Service industries, like consulting and training, would be hit. Hard. We'd be competing with other states, and companies who heavily use consultants would either have to lower their payments to offset the tax, increase what they pay (doubtful) or move out of state to avoid all of this extra cost. Like next door, to New Jersey, Ohio, Delaware...</p>

<p>Great idea, Governor. Tax one of the few vibrant industries as if we're all cans of soda and you want to raise revenue on our sugary attack on health. Except in this case, we're fueling innovation, growing successful businesses, incubating ideas and making things happen.</p>

<h2>How About Playing Against Type?</h2>

<p>If Donald Trump's profile is summed up as "Thunderous Arrogant Idiot", yours would probably be "Clueless Hack". Your inability to wrestle a decent budget for state education and support your professors and teachers, forcing the first strike in several decades at state universities, is one example. This is another. You're in a state with a majority Republican legislature, and you need an ideological win. This is not the one you should focus on. It raises taxes, it causes companies to re-evaluate their investment in PA and in tech companies, and it is wrong for our state.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-35913129.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Surface Pro 3 - For anyone who asks</title><category>Opinion</category><category>dual-boot</category><category>opinions</category><category>surface pro 3</category><category>ubuntu</category><category>windows</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/11/13/surface-pro-3-for-anyone-who-asks.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:35107068</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><span class="full-image-float-left ssNonEditable"><span><img src="http://rimple.com/storage/post-images/20141113_114753.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1415898290417" alt="" /></span></span>This is my review of a Surface Pro 3 I've been using as a travel-training machine for the past month. In short, I LoveHate it, but mostly love, as long as I put it in its place.</p>
<div><span class="full-image-block ssNonEditable">It's NOT a mac.&nbsp; It's NOT unix.&nbsp; It's limited. But not as much as an iPad or Android device - it's a fully-fledged machine.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>I got the i5 256GB 8GB RAM model. Nice, wish I would have spent on the larger storage option but it's not too bad.</div>
<h2>Ergonomics</h2>
<div>Typecover is OK, but notice the little LogitechOne nubbin on the end - works fantastically well with the USB radio and my various mice and keyboards.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The screen is gorgeous, touch is responsive.</div>
<h2>About that OS</h2>
<div>Windows 8.1 is meh (app store, well, sucks - maybe that will improve over time).</div>
<div></div>
<div>Cygwin is as horrible as I remember. When will Microsoft put bash in there? When?</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Windows 10 is a great upgrade but it's nowhere near ready yet for consumer use as it's just a beta. &nbsp;The pen acts up, the screen resolution management isn't there yet, but I really want it once it comes out. Biggest thing you lose? The pen top button (which launches OneNote when clicked) stops working, and all sorts of hacks don't do the right things.</div>
<h2>Google, whereforout my Google?&nbsp;</h2>
<div></div>
<div>Big pet peeve - you can't sync Google email to it or calendar unless your company ponies up for the paid version of Google Apps - Google dropped support from Apps for calendars and folder sync etc., and you have to use Google Apps sync - this is too expensive for that one feature IMO.</div>
<h2>What about Linux on that thing?</h2>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Ubuntu was FAN-TASTIC dual-booted. I spent hours tweaking it and getting the type cover working. Ultimately it was just easier to tote around some Logitech keyboards and mice. But then Windows 10 did a firmware update (just scroll down on my homepage to see the hate it fostered deep inside me) and blew away Grub. I couldn't recover from that, wanted back the drivers for Windows 8.1, and did a wipe. Sad, but needed. Maybe the open source movement in Microsoft we're hearing about will eventually soften their need to control the box, but I'm giving up for now. VMWare is sufficient for some development on Ubuntu in a pinch.</div>
<h2>Office Software</h2>
<div></div>
<div>I have Windows 365 on it, and that's a nice distribution. OneDrive is equally useful as Dropbox was. I now have OneDrive on my mac, as well as OneNote, so I can put files in a shared space and share my notes. OneNote blows Evernote out of the water in terms of note taking by hand with the stylus (and it is much better than S-Note on Samsung Galaxy devices) - but I don't like the way it does tags (tabs across the top of the UI). But it does have plugins, so I will look into options for easier navigation. There is an Evernote to Onenote importer if anyone else gets a cheaper i3 Surface or something, but it's one-way so keep that in mind.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Seriously, you should look at OneNote if you use Evernote - it is a click-and-type note taker that lets you embed free-form content where it makes sense, and search is pretty good. If you have good handwriting skills (or nunchuck skills, etc) it can search your handwritten notes too with background indexed OCR.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>One other note. My use case is that I wanted a teeny laptop to take out when I teach that is a full computer, and for taking to meetings for notetaking with the pen. Travel with one device rather than two. For that purpose, it's perfect.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<h2><span style="font-size: 1.5em;">For Developers?</span></h2>
<div></div>
<div>For a daily developer pad, maybe not so much (depends on the task)! &nbsp;(I used it this AM to do correspondence and email, and a bit of development, but I'm on the macbook pro right now, after admitting this to myself this week. I'm back with my buddy Mac for some of my work). If you're a web designer, photoshop user, artist, musician, etc., it's really a perfect device. Multi-core deep learning or hadoop? Nope, move on for now, the heat management isn't yet there to keep the cores humming, and you won't get enough space... The MicroSD card helps there, but it's not very fast. &nbsp;But, if you're comparing it to having two devices (a tablet and a laptop) yes, you can get a lot done with just this one.</div>
<div></div>
<h2>Happiness Graph for Surface Pro 3 and me</h2>
<p>This is my silly sketch take on whether I'm happy using this thing or not. Notice over time it has lots of bumps. inspired by <a class="offsite-link-inline" href="http://www.bennadel.com/blog/2439-my-experience-with-angularjs-the-super-heroic-javascript-mvw-framework.htm" target="_blank">this really silly blog post</a>&nbsp;about productivity with Angular 1.x, but executed SOO MUCH POORLY on OneNote with the Surface pen.</p>
<div></div>
<div><span class="full-image-block ssNonEditable"><span><img src="http://rimple.com/storage/post-images/Surface%20Pro%20Happiness.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1415898407148" alt="" /></span></span></div>
<p><span class="thumbnail-image-block ssNonEditable"><br /></span></p>
<div></div>]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-35107068.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Ubuntu on EFI-based Surface Pro 3 - My thoughts...</title><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 21:48:08 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/11/7/ubuntu-on-efi-based-surface-pro-3-my-thoughts.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:35099174</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Let me first start with the blog equivalent of a huge curse storm:</p>
<p style="font-size: 350%;">#$@^%#@&amp;$%@$%&amp;@!!!</p>
<h2><span class="caps">UPDATE</span></h2>
<p>I gave up on dual-boot. Mostly it was because I had nowhere safe to turn. I could boot Windows 10, a preview release, which doesn't work well with the Surface Pro 3, or I could <span class="caps">TRY </span>to boot Linux, which doesn't boot. Fail.</p>
<p>So, I decided to load Windows 8.1 back up again. But I couldn't easily. Why? Because I still had an existing Windows partition, and because of that, it would always load back Windows 10 with my downloaded restore image. I thought I was hosed, and found lots of people complaining about it. But it turns out I had to use diskpart.exe from my boot drive and clean the boot disk completely. This made it re-partition, and then I could install Windows 8.1. <strong><span class="caps">PHEW</span></strong>. It's <span class="caps">VMW</span>are for me for any Ubuntu-foolery.</p>
<h2>Back to the story...</h2>
<p >ok, with that out of my system....</p>
<h2><span class="caps">EFI </span>- Eww, For[insert-your-diety]sake, I [don't understand who architected this]</h2>
<p>Ok, I'm a geezer. The kind of guy whose teenage sons think "what a fat old slob." &nbsp;But in that slobbiness is a geek who doesn't give up lightly on his projects.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I'm about to give up on my project.</p>
<p>But somewhere along the line, Microsoft decided to screw us up. Royally. It seems that the screwup is the <span class="caps">EFI </span>bios.</p>
<p><span class="caps">EFI </span>is a new, lockable booting system. You <strong>can</strong>&nbsp;disable boot security, and then you <strong>should</strong>&nbsp;be able to load your favorite OS or dual boot. &nbsp;<strong>But</strong>, when Microsoft comes along with a firmware update, they decide to kill your boot sector. Screw you, Microsoft. What the hell are you thinking?</p>
<p>So, you can have a nice, working Linux instance, until your Windows updates come along and trash it. <span class="caps">WTF.</span> Who the hell thinks up this stuff, mad scientists?</p>
<p>I had such a nice system set up:</p>
<p>1. Boot into Windows 10, read my kindle, play music, work on Photoshop</p>
<p>2. Boot into Ubuntu native with Grub2, get all dirty with tech, yo.</p>
<p>3. Run <span class="caps">VMW</span>are Workstation on my Windows 10 instance, attach to the SD card and run my software almost as fast as native (yeah, but not completely as we've only got 8GB of ram on this thing)</p>
<p>So, somewhere after I reached #3 nirvana, a Firmware update went and trashed Grub, and now I'm back to no-matter-what-I'll-ignore-you-while-you-try-to-recover-your-grub-config-world. I've even tried re-installing Ubuntu completely on the partition, and now I can't figure out where the hell to put the Grub boot loader - is it /dev/sda, /dev/sda2 (the <span class="caps">EFI </span>partition), /dev/sda4 (the Windows partition), what?</p>
<p>Seriously, someone should take the person who decided to overwrite the boot sector out and [scene missing].</p>
<h2>Making the tablet safe for democracy, one boot at a time</h2>
<p>#$@^@#$%#$% (again I start cursing).</p>
<p>So, what gives Microsoft the feeling that they can just come along and lock us down? I've been a mac user for a decade, but only because it has a) better apps, b) <span class="caps">UNIX, </span>and c) better hardware. The surface is an awesome piece of kit physically, but what a waste it is if you can't use it as "god" intended - and since I'm agnostic, "god" is the developer. Me. The guy who purchased it.</p>
<h2>Make it stop, please!</h2>
<p>Hey, software companies. Stop your 'let's control the horizontal and the vertical' crap. It's really not necessary. Or at least give us a switch that turns off the stupid training wheels.</p>
<p>Why is <span class="caps">EFI </span>so damn hard to work with? Why can't we have the option to hack on our own machines? Somebody better start thinking about innovation before we all just have to sheeple ourselves into Windum 11, which will use a big crayon and give you a free binkie. Because I'm just not having this "trash your other crap" party anymore.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>And boot-repair doesn't help</h2>
<p>So, you use Boot Repair. It runs all the way through, then fails miserably. It even warns you about <span class="caps">EFI </span>- like telling you that you just passed the gates of hell and are headed to the abyss. Anything you check there? Ignored.</p>
<p>I've turned off the malware checks on startup, I've turned off secure boot, I've tried sprays and powders. Nothing works. Sigh. Yay me.</p>
<p>If I find the answer, I'll post it. Up top. And do a mea culpa.</p>
<p>Happy hunting, folks.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-35099174.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Get your Karma back with NVM</title><category>karma</category><category>node.js</category><category>nvm</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 14:59:58 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/5/20/get-your-karma-back-with-nvm.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34824491</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Have you noticed that the command-line Karma runner suddenly isn't being put in the NodeJS bin directory? Yeah, me too.  For people with a static NodeJS directory, installed via a package manager or hard install, you can just add this to the path:</p>

<pre><code>   path-to-nvm/lib/node_modules/karma/bin
</code></pre>

<p>But what if you use NVM? Especially on Linux and Mac, you have a pretty cool option, especially if you use a 'default' alias for your current node installation. Put this in your .bashrc script, after your source of the <code>nvm.sh</code> script:</p>

<pre><code>   export KARMA_DIR=~/.nvm/v`cat \
     ~/.nvm/alias/default`/lib/node_modules/karma/bin
   export PATH=$KARMA_DIR:$PATH
</code></pre>

<p>Then you're good to go!</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34824491.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Coming up May 22-23 - AngularJS Training at Chariot Solutions</title><category>chariot-news</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 20:17:25 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/5/14/coming-up-may-22-23-angularjs-training-at-chariot-solutions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34814326</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>If you were looking to take an AngularJS course, now is the time. We're offering a two-day fundamentals course on <a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/course/angularjs-fundamentals/">May 22-23</a> that covers:</p>

<ul>
<li>A primer on modern Javascript</li>
<li>Modules</li>
<li>Views and Routing</li>
<li>The Controller</li>
<li>Services </li>
<li>Directives</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/course/angularjs-fundamentals/">Register Today!</a></p>

<p>All of this and testing, focusing on Jasmine and the Karma test runner. You'll learn a lot in a short period of time. I hope to see some of you there.</p>

<p>If you are interested in a private training course offering, <a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/what-we-do/training/make-a-request/">drop us a line</a> at our website and we can discuss.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34814326.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Eclipse (or STS), Javascript, SPA and me... An open rant</title><category>eclipse</category><category>javascript</category><category>rants</category><category>spa</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 19:12:48 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/2/21/eclipse-or-sts-javascript-spa-and-me-an-open-rant-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34649769</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Ok, I just sent out a tweet I'll probably regret. But let me state my case: there is only one traditional editing company that 'gets' Javascript <span class="caps">IDE</span>s right now in the world of Single Page WebApps - and that's JetBrains. The other option is <span class="caps">VIM </span>for me...  Or Brackets (AWESOME tool). But I want my <span class="caps">CTRL</span>-SPACE code fill-in.</p>
<p>I've been running a training course that involves a JavaScript Single Page Web Application (SPA) in AngularJS. Like many of these platforms, it involves mounting a number of other JavaScript libraries, and they are generally mounted in a minified way unless you need to debug into them (long debate I'm side-stepping here).</p>
<p>My tweet about 30 minutes ago seems to have gotten legs, and I'm about to duck under an earthen barrier to avoid the flack:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Whomever has power over <span class="caps">STS </span>and Javascript tooling, can you play nice or integrate with <span class="caps">JSH</span>int and ignore my minified <span class="caps">SPA </span>libs?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Here is my challenge:</p>
<p>Given a Javascript-fronted single page Web Application, I want:</p>
<p>
<ul>
<li>Ability to run my <span class="caps">SPA </span>in a simple <span class="caps">HTTP </span>server quickly</li>
<li>Instant editing of my application scripts with <span class="caps">JSH</span>int right there in the problems panel, without redeploying or caching issues</li>
<li>Strongly integrated maven-based tools for hinting with <span class="caps">JSH</span>int</li>
<li>Strong integration with GruntJS - it's the Javascript <span class="caps">ANT </span>tool now</li>
<li>Integration with Bower to index the source of repositories that we've downloaded</li>
<li>Integration with NodeJS's dependencies to install tools, etc...</li>
<li>Native integration of Jasmine and Karma (if I have NodeJS integration) to run the tests, or maybe a test generator plugin to generate the test runner on the fly</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p>Is anyone in Eclipse-land working on this? The closest I've gotten to Javascript happiness is using WebStorm. But it doesn't support these tools directly (I have to execute them from a command prompt panel). I love WebStorm for its strong tooling, but even that one is missing Grunt as a plugin.</p>
<p>For clients who need to stay on Java-based build tools (because they're not switching their backend to Node/Express) but who are moving into <span class="caps">SPA </span>+ <span class="caps">REST</span>ful Spring/Java EE apps, I think we'd see good adoption of a forward-leaning Eclipse (since it is kind of the enterprise developer's lingua franca).</p>
<p>Am I off the mark here? Tell me so in the comments...</p>
<p>Ken</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34649769.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Javascript's new Development Tools</title><category>Javascript</category><category>tutorials</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 19:50:31 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2014/1/3/javascripts-new-development-tools-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34540707</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>After revamping Chariot's website and consolidating our blog, podcasts, screencast and other content to that area, I'm doing more technical blogging there.</p>

<p>I'm in the middle of writing up a series of blog posts concerning the new development tools that Javascript developers are wielding to get their jobs done.</p>

<p>Here are the posts as they exist now (I'll update this when we add new ones):</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/blog/post/javascript-modern-web-tools-intro/">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/blog/post/javascripts-modern-web-tools-node-package-manager/">The Node Package Manager</a></li>
<li><a href="http://chariotsolutions.com/blog/post/javascript-modern-web-tools-bower/">Bower</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Coming soon:</p>

<ul>
<li>Grunt</li>
<li>Yeoman</li>
</ul>

<p>Ken</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34540707.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Galaxy Gear Smartwatch Capsule Review</title><category>galaxy gear</category><category>smartwatch</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 13:58:45 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/12/29/galaxy-gear-smartwatch-capsule-review.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34531198</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><em>Update: I picked up a Pebble smartwatch - says is waterproof, 7+day battery life, limited features but mostly a watch with message integration.  Will post my impressions separately.</em></p>

<p>I did a bit of conspicuous consumption this weekend and picked up a Galaxy Gear smartwatch.  Here's my mini-review:</p>

<h2>Pros</h2>

<ul>
<li>It's <code>from the future</code></li>
<li>The display is awesome</li>
<li>Neat applications</li>
<li>Easy paring with Galaxy Note 3 using NFC</li>
<li>Great watch faces</li>
</ul>

<h2>Cons</h2>

<ul>
<li>24 hour battery life (or less)</li>
<li>HUGE, un-replaceable, inflexible band on account of the camera built in</li>
<li>Not waterproof</li>
<li>Huge cradle needed to charge</li>
<li>heavy to wear</li>
<li>I can't touch type on a macbook pro when it is on</li>
<li>SDK is not available from Samsung even though it's an Android device</li>
</ul>

<p>Ok, first off, WHY, Samsung, would you create a clasp that sticks out about 3mm from the watch band? Do you know most of your buyers are techies who might just use your watch while typing? Really, that's a fail right there. Secondly, instead of adding features like GPS (yeah, WHY?) to your devices couldn't you use a bit of that space to house a larger battery? And the ergonomics of it? Are there any?</p>

<p>I'm going with either a pebble smartwatch or if I feel a bit more futuristic a Sony Smartwatch 2 - we'll see. But I'm not sure who they are marketing this Galaxy Gear to at this point. Nerds who don't want to type but use their phones everywhere? It's not the future, it's like I'm P-Diddy with a Maybach on my wrist.</p>

<p>PS - I really wanted to like this thing. I just don't see how you could skip ergonomics completely and assume people will just learn how to deform their wrists to use it.  Hopefully they learn from this and produce a good watch for their next version, with 3 or more days of battery life, water proofing, and a replaceable strap (no, I DO NOT need a 1.8 megapixel camera).</p>

<p>The only reason I bought it was to program on it - I thought it would be nice to write a few early apps for the platform. But Samsung does not allow public access to the Gear SDK yet. That tells me they are planning on releasing a supportable watch with SDK in the future. I love the Galaxy Note 3 even with all of the bling (as it's a really useable Android platform phone) but this is just a heap of features dumped on a watch.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34531198.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Chariot's Data I/O 2013 - Be there or be O(2^n)</title><category>Announcements</category><category>chariot-news</category><category>conferences</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 18:31:51 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/9/20/chariots-data-io-2013-be-there-or-be-o2n.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34272401</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>(updated) Hey there folks. I'd like to alert you to a great one-day show we're putting on in Philadelphia on October 30th. But I'm tired of typing, so here it is in mind map glory:</p>

<p><a href="http://emergingtech.chariotsolutions.com/dataio2013"><img src="http://rimple.com/storage/post-images/data io silly.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1381258909668"/></a></p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34272401.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Hacking the 'Roo... Removing the default web plugins</title><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 16:20:48 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/9/20/hacking-the-roo-removing-the-default-web-plugins.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34272004</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Let's say you love the productivity of Roo up to a point, but that point happens to be the web. Unfortunately, the default Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>patterns installed in a Roo web app are pretty heavyweight - adding localization, tiles, tags, jspx, etc...</p>

<p>If you ever set up and then backed-out a Roo configuration for the web, and then did the wrong thing and found it regenerated the default web site scaffold, you may have sighed under your breath that you just wish Roo didn't do that.</p>

<p>Well, you have an option. I'd say it's rather voodoo, but if you want to get prototyping in some web-based applications and just make a simple Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>front-end, but don't want to get Roo involved in anything above, say, the service tier, here's what you can do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Make a custom Roo installation directory</li>
<li>Expand Roo</li>
<li>remove the bundles for web, webmvc, web-json, gwt, jsf, selenium (and maybe one or two more I can't remember)</li>
<li>remove the cache directory from Roo (it copies the deployed add-ons into this cache as part of the Equinox <span class="caps">OSG</span>i container).</li>
<li>start up Roo, and see if it sends any <span class="caps">OSG</span>i errors your way. If it does, you've forgotten to remove a bundle. Try again - shut down the shell, follow the removal step, clear the cache directory, and  restart.</li>
</ul>

<p>There you are. Now, you can enjoy using Roo for the Aspect-J <span class="caps">ITD</span>s, and to make modeling data easier, but if you are simply using Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>for a <span class="caps">REST</span>ful front-end, now Roo doesn't get in your way anymore.</p>

<p>You can always link your roo.sh shell script for this version of roo to something like /usr/bin/roo-lite.</p>

<p>Happy Roo'ing.</p>

<p>Ken</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34272004.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Accessing and writing client-created cookies in AngularJS</title><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 15:31:53 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/7/11/accessing-and-writing-client-created-cookies-in-angularjs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:34002752</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>AngularJS provides a $cookieStore object that reads and writes cookies. Here is a sample JSFiddle (my new favorite toy) that demonstrates setting a cookie value and bumping it by one each time the button is clicked.</p>
<p>Note - you won't see the number bump in the iFrame-embedded JSFiddle... Only if you jump to the JSFiddle site to test with it! This is Cross-Site Scripting protection in action...</p>
<iframe width="100%" height="300" src="http://jsfiddle.net/krimple/9dSb2/embedded/" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0"></iframe>
<p><em>Original discussion source was <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10961963/how-to-access-cookies-in-angularjs">this Stack Overflow article</a>.</em></p>]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-34002752.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spring Roo 1.2.4.RELEASE available now</title><category>News</category><category>Spring Roo</category><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 13:50:46 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/6/17/spring-roo-124release-available-now.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:33913238</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/alankstewart">@alankstewart</a> and some new contributors from the open source community, Spring Roo 1.2.4 has been released. It is available for <a href="http://www.springsource.org/download/community?project=Spring%2520Roo">download now</a>.</p>

<p>Fifty issues have been <a href="https://jira.springsource.org/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20ROO%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%20%221.2.4.RELEASE%22%20AND%20status%20%3D%20Resolved%20ORDER%20BY%20priority%20DESC">resolved</a> and it looks like the twitter tweet has been removed from the shell. </p>

<p>I'll be digging around with this a bit and posting any tidbits - I am also going to upgrade the code samples for Roo in Action to 1.2.4 this week, and will post any notes on what I find during upgrades.</p>

<p>Ken</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-33913238.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>AngularJS Pattern #1 - async service results</title><category>angularjs</category><category>tips and tricks</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 16:32:56 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/5/24/angularjs-pattern-1-async-service-results.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:33758194</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>In Angular, everything is asynchronous as much as possible to provide speed. A call to a <code>$http</code> service, which performs ajax methods, doesn't immediately return a value. If you decide to split up your Angular controllers and services, so you separate your UI from the calls to your backends, you'll quickly find that it becomes hard to get a response without some extra work.</p>]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-33758194.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spring Roo project updates...</title><category>Spring Roo</category><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/5/4/spring-roo-project-updates.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:33557879</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>It's been a while and all has been quiet on my front - I've been buried with day-job work, and enjoying not having to update a book in a while :)</p>

<p>A quick note on Spring Roo - looks like there are plans for a 1.2.4 release sometime in the summer. Alan Stewart tweeted this earlier in the week.  Also, the Roobot, which accepts new <span class="caps">OSG</span>i bundles and also provides for downloading of existing ones, went down for a while, but due to some work recently by Alan it's up and running for internal bundles as of today. </p>

<p>If you're using Roo and need some basic Roo-provided bundles, they are now online. </p>

<p>Alan is working on getting the Roobot stabilized (some project descriptor might be causing trouble, we'll have to see which one - at one point it was mine). Once that's done they can re-populate the repository with the user-contributed ones.</p>

<p>Finally, the download link seems to be broken (the initial Download button works, but once you bypass registration and go to the download form, the real link is not a link), but follow my reply on <a href="http://forum.springsource.org/showthread.php?137026-Download-link-broken">this forum thread</a> for a quick workaround.</p>

<p>Once Roo 1.2.4 gets ready for takeoff, I'll post my notes on it. I've recently submitted a contributor agreement to help Alan with some things here and there, and if they accept it, I'll be able to do a bit more for the community.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-33557879.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Quizzo - it's baaack - but this time for keeps</title><category>ETE</category><category>angularjs</category><category>quizzo</category><category>quizzo-ete-2013</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/2/16/quizzo-its-baaack-but-this-time-for-keeps.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:32816474</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hey everybody!</p>

<p>For my <span class="caps">ETE </span>talk, and our internal Chariot Day conference beforehand, I've taken on client-side Single-Page-Web-Application (SPWA) Javascript programming. I started by attempting to learn Backbone.js, but this poor old server-side programmer with a smattering of front-end talents grounded hard on the shallow waters of confusion.</p>

<p>I was not alone. At SpringOne/2GX 2012, VMware's Craig Walls hosted a talk comparing <span class="caps">SPWA </span>frameworks, and discussed Backbone's lack of a 'day one story' - a starting point example. He was really interested in the Walmart Labs projects <a href="http://walmartlabs.github.com/thorax/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Thorax</a> and <a href="http://walmartlabs.github.com/lumbar/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Lumbar</a>, which are attempting to bring some higher-level structure and organization to the code base. Also, I ran into the emerging but not yet complete <a href="http://yeoman.io/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Yeoman</a>   <br />
Then Chariot's <a href="https://twitter.com/doncoleman">Don Coleman</a> turned me on to Addy Osmani's <a href="http://todomvc.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">TodoMVC project</a> - it implements the same task list use case in oh, about 18+ frameworks.  </p>

<p>I spent time looking at each of them and AngularJS caught my eye. It has two-way instant data synchronization, is agnostic with respect to your models, contains a good basic validation scheme, and uses tags and attributes salted to the templates to expose a 'ViewModel' to the view.</p>

<h3>What is a view model?</h3>

<p>A ViewModel is an element of your <span class="caps">MVC </span>model that should be exposed to the page. Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>has this concept - we put things in the Model object to show to the users, but rarely do we put true domain objects in there. If  you have web-only beans that you send back-and-forth to the <span class="caps">UI, </span>chances are you're using the ViewModel pattern (please let me know if that is a wrong assumption).</p>

<h3>A sample view</h3>

<p>Let's review some code from our current Quizzo-ETE project, a collaboration with David Turanski of VMware for our upcoming Modern Spring Web Applications talk.  We're using AngularJS and Spring to show enterprise developers  how to leverage their skills in Spring but also quickly get onboard with a very powerful <span class="caps">SPWA </span>framework.</p>

<p>First, a simple view fragment, showing how to emit model elements:</p>



<pre class="brush: html">
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th span=&quot;2&quot;&gt;Statistics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Score&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;{{statistics.score}}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Max Score&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;{{statistics.maxScore}}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;% Correct&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;{{statistics.percentCorrect}}&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

</pre>



<p>So, you can see the handlebars-style substitutions of ViewModel elements using the <code>{{</code> and <code>}}</code> characters. </p>

<h3>A sample Angular controller </h3>

<p>Here is the Angular controller that put the data in there in the first place:</p>



<pre class="brush: javascript">
myApp.controller('ByeCtrl', function($scope) {
  $scope.statistics = {
    &quot;score&quot;: &quot;130&quot;,
    &quot;maxScore&quot;: &quot;150&quot;,
    &quot;percentCorrect&quot;: &quot;86%&quot;,
    &quot;topScorers&quot;: ['phil', 'joe', 'alex']
  };
</pre>



<p>The <code>$scope</code> object is our ViewModel. We're adding a Javascript object called </p>

<pre>statistics</pre>

<p> to it, hardcoding it for now. </p>

<h3>Two-way databinding</h3>

<p>The cool thing is that if anything on the page changes the objects, the page changes immediately. A click, an event, even a message from the outside world, can trigger a UI update. The same works the other direction with form elements. Consider this fragment:</p>



<pre class="brush: html">
  &lt;form class=&quot;panelform left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;label for=&quot;nickname&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nickname&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; 
               ng-model=&quot;nickname&quot;
               ng-change=&quot;verify_nick(nickname)&quot;
               id=&quot;nickname&quot;
                /&gt; 
        &lt;span ng-show=&quot;badNick&quot; class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;
                        Nickname already used...&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;button id=&quot;join&quot; ng-click=&quot;join_game($location)&quot;
      ng-show=&quot;!badNick &amp;&amp; nickname&quot;&gt;Join&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</pre>



<h3>Handling events</h3>

<p>The input tag has some special attributes in it - <code>ng-model</code>, which automatically binds the typed in value (live, no less, not even requiring a submit) to a <code>$scope</code> element called <code>nickname</code>. We trigger verification by calling a controller method called <code>verify_nick</code>, passing the nickname into the call. Here is what the controller looks like:</p>



<pre class="brush: javascript">
myApp.controller('JoinCtrl', function ($scope, $location, PlayerService, QuizManagerService) {

  $scope.verify_nick = function () {
    var result = PlayerService.searchNickName($scope.nickname);
    $scope.badNick = result;
  };

  $scope.join_game = function (nickName, emailAddress) {
    PlayerService.setNickName(nickname);
    QuizManagerService.startQuiz();
    $location.path(&quot;/play&quot;);
  };


});
</pre>



<p>You can see interactions with several objects. For Spring fans, we inject objects in a similar way to how Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>does it - add it to the function's parameter list and it gets injected. <span class="caps">NICE.</span></p>

<h3>Services </h3>

<p>We inject and use several objects:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>$scope</code> - our ViewModel</li>
<li><code>$location</code> - allows us to change the page fragment we're showing</li>
<li><code>PlayerService, QuizManagerService</code> - these are <em>stateful</em> service objects that live inside of the browser. Think of them as holding your state and calling business methods, and you're on the right track.</li>
</ul>

<p>You should note that in this function, we're adding two other named functions to the <code>ViewModel</code> - <code>verify_nick</code> and <code>join_game</code>. Also, for those Spring developers you'll see us delegating most work to our named Service and built-in Angular objects. Just like a good <span class="caps">MVC, </span>it's just a front-end. The services do all the work.</p>

<h3>Summary </h3>

<p>That's all for now, and if you check out the commit with version <code>33607951b734a0f1cfc8a710b41abd8664cc3e8f</code> you can run the app this way:</p>

<ul>
<li>first, install node.js - 0.8 +</li>
<li>next, do a 'npm install -g express'</li>
<li>cd to ./angular-prototype/app</li>
<li>run the server with <code>node server.js</code></li>
<li>browse to http://localhost:4567</li>
</ul>

<p>It looks <span class="caps">TERRIBLE </span>right now. But it is a working app with several panes. I'm using Twitter bootstrap on the front-end so expect some ugliness until I get that smoothed out.</p>

<p>To re-iterate, our code is online - please feel free to watch our progress and comment away here if you like, but expect lots of silly steps as we move along). It's at <a href="http://github.com/krimple/quizzo-ete" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">http://github.com/krimple/quizzo-ete</a>.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-32816474.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Philly Emerging Tech 2013 - sold out!!</title><category>Philly ETE</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 15:16:10 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/2/16/philly-emerging-tech-2013-sold-out.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:32816461</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps it's a bit expected, but the 2013 Emerging Technologies for the Enterprise conference just sold out yesterday. As before, it sold out at the end of the early bird registration, so everybody saved $75! </p>

<p>We have a <span class="caps">FANTASTIC </span>show coming up. Just look at the website, <a href="http://phillyemergingtech.com" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">phillyemergingtech.com</a>, and you'll see. We have Doug Lea, Cliff Click, Ken Scwaber, Aaron Patterson, the committers of at least five or six javascript single-page and server frameworks, and the list goes on, and on.</p>

<p>As we did last year, we <span class="caps">ARE </span>going to record the screens this year of almost every talk (forgive us if we have a technical glitch or two).  We won't be streaming live, but we will be doing our best to get the talks out when we can. </p>

<p>So, if you aren't able to go, within a few months we should have the talks available online. Watch the @Chariotsolution or @krimple twitter accounts for the announcements. And you can browse all of our other content at our content site, <a href="http://emergingtech.chariotsolutions.com" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">emergingtech.chariotsolutions.com</a>, including just about all of the 2012 talks, our Science of Big Data conference materials, and over 100 podcasts from the past five years.</p>

<p>Ken</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-32816461.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Philly Emerging Tech April 2-3 2013 - Register today!</title><category>ETE</category><category>News</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 16:25:40 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2013/1/4/philly-emerging-tech-april-2-3-2013-register-today.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:32382630</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Remember that conference in the spring? Well, it's baaack! Yep, it's 2013, and so we are full-steam ahead, planning for the next <a href="http://phillyemergingtech.com" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Emerging Technologies for the Enterprise</a> Conference, to be held at the Sheraton Olde City in beautiful Philadelphia on April 2-3.</p>

<p>We have quite the show lined up for you, with keynotes from <a href="https://twitter.com/richhickey" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Rich Hickey</a>, the creator of the <a href="http://clojure.org/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Clojure language</a>, and <a href="http://m6d.com/">Media Six Degrees</a>' Chief Data Scientist, <a href="http://metamarkets.com/2012/data-scientist-profile-claudia-perlich-chief-scientist-at-m6d/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Claudia Perlich</a>. Notable speakers include <a href="http://emberjs.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Ember.js</a> creator (<a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2012/12/07/im-running-to-reform-the-w3cs-tag/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">among</a> <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2012/04/13/tokaido-my-hopes-and-dreams/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">other</a> <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/core" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">things</a>) <a href="http://yehudakatz.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Yehuda Katz</a>, <a href="http://web.mit.edu/jesstess/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Jessica McKellar</a> of the <a href="http://twitter.com/bostonpython" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Boston Python User Group</a>, <a href="http://twistedmatrix.com/trac/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">contributor</a> to the Python Twisted async network library, the inimitable <a href="http://tenderlovemaking.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Aaron Patterson</a> (if you want a laugh, listen to him rib us about our conference name in his <a href="http://wharton6.mediasite.com/mediasite/Play/cc319b19847a40b293cd23ab5db479d91d?catalog=216aac01-e4cb-42cd-8c4e-aaf681778f06" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Code Chacuterie talk of 2012</a>)... </p>

<p>Also we have <a href="http://www.infoq.com/author/Cliff-Click" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Cliff Click</a> (0xdata), author of "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Java-Performance-Charlie-Hunt/dp/0137142528" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Java Performance</a>" <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/javaspotlight/entry/java_spotlight_episode_49_charlie" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Charlie Hunt</a>, <a href="http://golang.org/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline"></a>Go contributor and creator of <a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Sinatra</a> <a href="https://github.com/bmizerany" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Blake Mizerany</a>, author of "<a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Culture-Game-Tools-Manager/dp/0984875301" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">The Culture Game - Tools for the Agile Manager</a>" <a href="http://newtechusa.net/dan-mezick/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Dan Mezick</a>, <a href="http://www.jurgenappelo.com/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Jurgen Appelo</a> (author of <a href="http://www.management30.com/product/management30/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Management 3.0</a>), the creator of the <a href="http://scrum.com" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Scrum process</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ken_Schwaber" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Ken Schwaber</a>, and more are being added every day.</p>

<p>We even have Angluar.js expert Lukas Ruebbelke (see <a href="http://angularjs.org/" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">Angular.js</a>), a Google-sponsored "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-page_application" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">single page Javascript</a>" client-side application framework that uses <span class="caps">JSON</span>/REST and has live two-way data binding. (I didn't even realize we booked him when I published this so ignore my earlier version where I said I am speaking on this topic). And as usual we'll be recording sessions and hopefully podcasting too.</p>

<p>More speakers are being booked each week.  </p>

<p>So, don't delay. Last year we sold out with two months to go, and I think as we add additional awesome speakers the competition for a ticket will get intense. Register today at <a href="http://phillyemergingtech.com" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">phillyemergingtech.com</a>.</p>

<p>If you want more incentives, the early bird registration is just $385, and ends on February 15th. After that prices go up to $450 (still a steal, but why not save and register now, will ya?)</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-32382630.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>The future of Web MVC testing</title><category>Tips</category><category>spring</category><category>spring mvc</category><category>testing</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 23:12:12 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/12/19/the-future-of-web-mvc-testing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:32104260</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Ok, ok, I'm excited. Right now I just was able to hack my way through a test with Spring 3.2 and the new test web context.</p>

<p>The method I ended up writing looked like this:</p>



<pre class="brush: java">
@Test
public void tryStartQuiz() throws Exception {
   this.mvc.perform(get(&quot;/engine/start/james&quot;))
        .andExpect(status().isOk())
        .andExpect(content().contentType(MediaType.APPLICATION_JSON))
        .andExpect(jsonPath(&quot;$.quiz_id&quot;).exists());
}
</pre>



<h3>How did I get here? </h3>

<p>I upgraded to Spring 3.2, which has native support for loading Web contexts (well, not in a separate-but-parent/child way where you can mount the web context and business context separately, that's coming, but in one context).</p>

<p>Here is the top of my test class:</p>



<pre class="brush: java;">

import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.request.MockMvcRequestBuilders.*;
import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.result.MockMvcResultMatchers.*;
import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.setup.MockMvcBuilders.*;

@WebAppConfiguration
@RunWith(SpringJUnit4ClassRunner.class)
@ContextConfiguration(locations = {
   &quot;file:src/main/webapp/WEB-INF/spring/webmvc-config.xml&quot;, 
   &quot;classpath:/META-INF/spring/applicationContext.xml&quot;})
public class EngineControllerTest {

    @Autowired
    WebApplicationContext context;

    MockMvc mvc;

    @Before
    public void setUp() {
        mvc = webAppContextSetup(this.context).build();
    }

    ...

</pre>



<h3>Some analysis...</h3>

<p>The <code>MockMvc</code> object, which I referred to as <code>this.mvc</code> in my test, allows me to mock up the web container request and record expectations. It is created in the <code>@Before</code> method, after Spring injects a test <code>WebApplicationContext</code> object, which is driven via the <code>@WebAppConfiguration</code> above. </p>

<p>The <code>WebApplicationContext</code> object is a web app engine in a test engine. It boots a Spring <span class="caps">MVC </span>platform, mocking the network engine so that you can submit requests with calls like <code>mvc.perform(get(...) ...</code> and chain assertions, using <code>.andExpect</code> statements to build conditions. It's like headless Spring <span class="caps">MVC.</span> This allows you to test by submitting <span class="caps">URL</span>s but without having to configure Jetty or Tomcat in a complex server bootstrapped integration test.</p>

<h3>But where is it looking for my webapp?</h3>

<p>As a nice touch, the default path for the web application is <code>src/main/webapp</code>. If you're not mavenized, or have a test version of your webapp you want to use, you can submit the path to it as the value of the annotation, like:</p>

<code>@WebApplicationContext(&quot;src/test/lightweightwebapp&quot;)</code>

<h3>Assertions and matchers</h3>

<p>There are several static imports that make life easier, as outlined in this great slide show from the <a href="http://rstoyanchev.github.com/spring-32-test-webapps" target="_blank"><span class="caps">MVC </span>team (Rossen and friends)</a>:</p>



<pre class="brush: java;">
import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.request.MockMvcRequestBuilders.*;
import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.result.MockMvcResultMatchers.*;
import static org.springframework.test.web.servlet.setup.MockMvcBuilders.*;
</pre>



<p>I had to hack a bit with the commands and don't have the <span class="caps">DSL </span>figured out much so far. But it is nice to test through the request dispatcher rather than inject a controller directly. It's more natural and lets you really test the way production will handle your requests/responses.</p>

<h3>What about more sophisticated checks?</h3>

<p>The expect syntax doesn't really allow dicing and slicing of the response as easily as grabbing it in a variable. You can tell the mock <span class="caps">MVC </span>object to return the result, which contains the MockHttpServletResponse. In this example, I'm using FlexJson (from Roo's dependencies) to deserialize the <span class="caps">JSON </span>request into a HashMap of string keys and values, and assert that the data exists in the proper format.</p>



<pre class="brush: java">
@Test
public void tryStartQuiz() throws Exception {
	JSONDeserializer&lt;HashMap&lt;String, String&gt;&gt; deserializer
			= new JSONDeserializer&lt;HashMap&lt;String, String&gt;&gt;();

	MvcResult result = this.mvc.perform(get(&quot;/engine/start/james&quot;))
			.andExpect(status().isOk())
			.andExpect(content().contentType(MediaType.APPLICATION_JSON))
			.andExpect(jsonPath(&quot;$.quiz_id&quot;).exists())
			.andReturn();

	Map&lt;String, String&gt; jsonPayload =
			deserializer.deserialize(
					result.getResponse().getContentAsString());

	assertThat(jsonPayload.containsKey(&quot;quiz_id&quot;), is(true));
	assertThat(jsonPayload.get(&quot;nickname&quot;), is(&quot;james&quot;));

	System.err.println(jsonPayload);


}

</pre>



<h3>Roo and Spring 3.2 </h3>

<p>One more thing - I came from Roo 1.2.2, and as I upgraded the spring.version property to Spring 3.2 (yes, it works just fine) so I had to add one dependency in order for this to work, test scoped:</p>



<pre class="brush: xml;">
&lt;dependency&gt;
	&lt;groupId&gt;com.jayway.jsonpath&lt;/groupId&gt;
	&lt;artifactId&gt;json-path&lt;/artifactId&gt;
	&lt;version&gt;0.8.1&lt;/version&gt;
	&lt;scope&gt;test&lt;/scope&gt;
&lt;/dependency&gt;
</pre>



<p>Roo was just upgraded to version 1.2.3 this week (check it out <a href="http://www.springsource.org/spring-roo">here</a>). I am hoping it uses Spring 3.2 out of the box. </p>

<p>This test will be checked into the next update of Quizzo-Angular-Roo - my current obsession which is using Spring Roo on the backend, and Angular.JS on the front-end, for a single-page JS quiz engine. </p>

<h3>Where to go to view the code?</h3>

<p>Today I've pushed this code (somewhat modified) along with working Jasmine tests, <span class="caps">AND </span>a working Maven test suite that includes automatic Jasmine testing every time I run <code>mvn test</code>. Check it out at <a href="https://github.com/krimple/quizzo-angular-roo">quizzo-angular-roo on GitHub</a>. I warn you, it will be primitive and so far not really doing much, but it will shape up over time.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-32104260.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>todo-txt - very cool GTD task management from anything</title><category>productivity</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 00:46:17 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/11/20/todo-txt-very-cool-gtd-task-management-from-anything.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:31118764</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>So, just I stumbled on Gina Tripani's todo-txt project when searching for a cross-device todo management system. I am switching from an iPhone to an Android device as I'm prepping to provide some Android training for Chariot in the early part of next year. </p>

<p>todo-txt is a very simple format. Described <a href="http://todotxt.com/">here</a> and with a client for virtually anything (including the command-line, vim, Android, iOS, even WebOS) you can use it from anything, even a text editor. The clients are all savvy with Dropbox, so putting it on ~/Dropbox/todo is all you need to do.</p>

<p>Here is a groovy script I just wrote up to play with my todo list...</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
def todoFile = new File('./todo.txt')
def fileReader = new FileReader(todoFile)
def todos = fileReader.readLines()
def projects = [:], contexts = [:]
todos.each { it -&gt;
  println it
  def tokenizer = new StringTokenizer(it)
  while (tokenizer.hasMoreTokens()) {
      def token = tokenizer.nextToken()
      if (token.startsWith(&quot;@&quot;)) {
          def size = contexts[token] ? contexts[token] : 0
          contexts[token] = size + 1
      }
      if (token.startsWith(&quot;+&quot;)) {
          def size = projects[token] ? projects[token] : 0
          projects[token] = size + 1
      }
    
  }
}
fileReader.close()

projects.each { key, value -&gt; 
  println &quot;Project ${key} : ${value} tasks&quot;
}

println &quot;&quot;
contexts.each { key, value -&gt; 
  println &quot;context ${key} : ${value} tasks&quot;
}

</pre>



<p>Fun, eh? Now I can rid myself of the OS X reminders system - although I could really use the ability to store these in my Google calendar as timed events with due dates... Hmm...</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-31118764.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>STS 3.1.0.RELEASE - not loving Spock / Groovy for ADJT projects</title><category>SpringSource Roo</category><category>SpringSource Tool Suite</category><category>Technology News</category><category>groovy</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 14:33:37 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/10/21/sts-310release-not-loving-spock-groovy-for-adjt-projects.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:29970718</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>At SpringOne/2GX I tried the updated Springsource Tool Suite, 3.1.0, running a pre-4.0 Eclipse (as the <span class="caps">STS</span> 3.1.0 version is a bit tricky on Eclipse 4 until the 3.x - 4.0 migration bugs settle down).</p>

<p>Turns out there is a new error that shows up if you try to run anything Groovy within a <span class="caps">AJDT </span>project (which is the AspectJ Developer Tools plug-in Roo requires to compile all *.aj files when you're using them in the <span class="caps">IDE</span>).</p>

<p>You'll get:</p>



<pre class="brush: bash;">
Error compiling Groovy project: Either the Groovy-JDT patch is not installed or JavaBuilder is not being used.
</pre>



<p>I realize from talking to one of the developers at SpringOne that there have been some issues with the way Groovy handles AspectJ compiled classes, and that using Groovy within a Spring Roo project as general code it won't work properly, but this puts a damper on Spock at least from within the <span class="caps">STS IDE.</span> I can still run my tests from IntelliJ, however.</p>

<p>I'm going to post a request in the forums that we can turn off this error, so that we can use Spock for testing. So far, at least with Roo add-ons, I have used it to great effect and productivity, so at least for that use case I'd like to have an option to turn it off.</p>

<p>More soon.</p>

<p>Ken</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-29970718.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>More Spock love - how I tested complex install scenarios</title><category>Spring Roo</category><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 18:29:31 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/10/4/more-spock-love-how-i-tested-complex-install-scenarios.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:29636421</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm in love. Officially. With Spock.</p>

<p>Ok, we've only been hanging out for a little bit, here and there. But one of the things I'm doing is prepping for an updated talk on Spring Roo add-ons at SpringOne/2GX. Rather than repeat the same things again, I wanted to show some practical help for people writing add-ons, things like how to write good tests.</p>

<p>Also, I wanted to point out a few things that need more work, bring up some issues for the <span class="caps">JIRA </span>queue, so that we can improve Roo further after SpringOne. We'll get to that later in this article.</p>

<h3>Testing add-on availability</h3>

<p>Testing whether an add-on setup command is available to expose to the Roo shell can be a bit tricky. For example, in the Spock Roo add-on, I expect that the user's shell is:</p>

<ul>
<li>running in a project context</li>
<li>the project has to contain two maven dependencies for spock-core and spock-spring</li>
<li>the project has to contain one dependency for the gmaven-plugin to run Spock tests</li>
</ul>

<p>So, there are several scenarios to test. I started down the road to testing them all individually. Bad developer. First off, there is a sort of truth table here:</p>


<table><tr><th>installedDependencies</th><th>installedPlugins</th><th>expectedResult</th></tr><tr><td>none</td><td>none</td><td>true</td></tr><tr><td>depa, depb</td><td>none</td><td>true</td></tr><tr><td>depa</td><td>plugin</td><td>true</td></tr><tr><td>baddep</td><td>none</td><td>true</td></tr><tr><td>depa, depb</td><td>plugin</td><td>false</td></tr><tr><td>depabadversion, depb</td><td>plugin</td><td>true</td></tr></table>

<p><strong>Given</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li>depa and depb = the correct two Maven dependencies, </li>
<li>baddep is a Maven dependency completely unrelated </li>
<li>depabadversion is the same dependency but a different version </li>
<li>plug-in is the gmaven-plugin from codehaus</li>
<li>expectedResult is whether or not we can go ahead and install the add-on (i.e. replace what is there)</li>
</ul>

<p>As I started the third method I saw so much duplication I started to back off. First I removed whatever extra calls I was making to various methods (such as projectOperations.getDependencies()) which made it easier to test (and debug).  Then, I pulled out the data table syntax. </p>

<p>Here is what I ended up with. Totally boss, <span class="caps">BTW</span>:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
package org.sillyweasel.roo.addons.spock
import org.springframework.roo.project.Dependency
import org.springframework.roo.project.Plugin
import org.springframework.roo.project.ProjectOperations
import org.springframework.roo.project.maven.Pom
import spock.lang.Unroll

class SpockOperationsImplTest extends spock.lang.Specification {

  static def depa = 
    new Dependency(&quot;org.springframework&quot;, &quot;spock-core&quot;, &quot;0.6-groovy-1.8&quot;)
  static def depb = 
    new Dependency (&quot;org.springframework&quot;, &quot;spock-spring&quot;, &quot;0.6-groovy-1.8&quot;)
  static def depabadversion =
    new Dependency(&quot;org.springframework&quot;, &quot;spock-core&quot;, &quot;0.6-groovy-1.0&quot;)
  static def baddep = 
    new Dependency (&quot;org.springframework&quot;, &quot;sbad&quot;, &quot;0.6-groovy-1.8&quot;)
  static def plugin = 
    new Plugin(&quot;org.codehaus.gmaven&quot;, &quot;gmaven-plugin&quot;, &quot;1.4&quot;)


  @Unroll
  def &quot;install check - #situation&quot;() {
    given:
      def pom = Mock(Pom.class)
      def operations = new SpockOperationsImpl()
      def projectOperations = Mock(ProjectOperations.class)
      operations.projectOperations = projectOperations

    when:
      def commandAvailable = operations.isSetupCommandAvailable()

    then:
      1 * projectOperations.isFocusedProjectAvailable() &gt;&gt; true
      1 * projectOperations.getFocusedModule() &gt;&gt; pom
      1 * pom.getDependencies() &gt;&gt; deps
      pom.getBuildPlugins() &gt;&gt; plugins
      assert commandAvailable == res

    where:
    deps          | plugins | res   | situation
    []            | []      | true  | &quot;no installedDependencies or installedPlugin&quot;
    [ depa, depb] | []      | true  | &quot;all installedDependencies...
                                      but no installedPlugin&quot;
    [ depa ]      | [plugin]| true  | &quot;some installedDependencies...
                                       and installedPlugin&quot;
    [ baddep ]    | []      | true  | &quot;a different dependency and no plugins&quot;
    [ depa, depb ]| [plugin]| false | &quot;all installedDependencies and installedPlugin&quot;
    [ depabadversion, depb ] 
                  | [plugin] | true | &quot;bad version of a plugin&quot;
  }
}

</pre>



<h3>What's even better...</h3>

<p>See the method name at the top? It has an embedded hash mark, and uses the `situation` field, plus the `@Unroll` annotation, to turn the method into five separate test methods on the fly at test time.  Niiiice!</p>

<h2>Roo's challenges - addon testing</h2>

<p>Why am I doing all of my testing in Groovy when Roo is a Java-based framework? Three reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to get rolling on add-ons, </li>
<li>I need to understand the weaknesses of the add-on <span class="caps">API </span>so I can try to help improve it, </li>
<li>I need to make sure I test the most code for the least effort!</li>
</ul>

<p>To the middle point: Roo is based on Maven and Spring. It manages a Maven `pom.xml` file, as well as Spring, Java and other artifacts.</p>

<p>Because the Maven files are managed by some Java wrapper classes, written for the purpose of generating Maven <span class="caps">POM</span>s, they are currently good enough - you can fill them via an Xml <span class="caps">DOM, </span>for example, but they aren't inherently testable.</p>

<p>For example, the Pom class can't be mocked, so I can't inject a fake set of dependencies or plugins. That is, unless I install two Maven test dependencies, both of which <em>Spock told me to use as a helpful hint!</em> They are: `cglib-nodep` for mocking interface-less classes, and `objenesis` for creating instances of classes as Mocks without no-arg constructors. To wit:</p>



<pre class="brush: xml;">
&lt;dependency&gt;
  &lt;groupId&gt;cglib&lt;/groupId&gt;
  &lt;artifactId&gt;cglib-nodep&lt;/artifactId&gt;
  &lt;version&gt;2.2.2&lt;/version&gt;
  &lt;scope&gt;test&lt;/scope&gt;
&lt;/dependency&gt;

&lt;dependency&gt;
  &lt;groupId&gt;org.objenesis&lt;/groupId&gt;
  &lt;artifactId&gt;objenesis&lt;/artifactId&gt;
  &lt;version&gt;1.2&lt;/version&gt;
  &lt;scope&gt;test&lt;/scope&gt;
&lt;/dependency&gt;
</pre>



<p>With that, I can use:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
def pom = Mock(Pom.class)
</pre>



<h3>See you at SpringOne/2GX</h3>

<p>I'll be talking about this and other techniques at SpringOne/2GX in two weeks, and I'll post my presentation later as well. I hope to see some of you there.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-29636421.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>My Roo add-ons talk at SpringOne/2GX is approved</title><category>chariot-news</category><category>speaking-engagements</category><category>spring-roo</category><category>springone-2gx</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 20:04:03 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/9/11/my-roo-add-ons-talk-at-springone2gx-is-approved.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:28634713</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hello there. I'll be speaking about Spring Roo add-ons again at SpringOne/2GX this year. If you're heading to the show and want to talk shop on Roo and other things, seek me out. I'll be happy to chat.</p>

<p>Here is a <a href="http://www.springone2gx.com/conference/washington/2012/10/session?id=27797" target="_blank" class="offsite-link-inline">link to the talk</a>.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-28634713.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Speaking at SpringOne/2GX - topic - Roo add-ons</title><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 12:24:16 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/8/23/speaking-at-springone2gx-topic-roo-add-ons.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:24733772</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Hello, viewers. I've just received word that I'll be speaking at SpringOne/2GX this year. No link yet but I'm working on that. I'll be down there all week, so I hope to see you there.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-24733772.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Watch my SpringSource Roo add-ons video w/Srini Penchikala and SpringSource's Josh Long</title><category>Screencasts</category><category>chariot-news</category><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 02:34:40 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/8/19/watch-my-springsource-roo-add-ons-video-wsrini-penchikala-an.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:24127241</guid><description><![CDATA[<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_VMmzaUxE0c?feature=player_detailpage" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-24127241.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spock's data tables are sweet!</title><category>Spock</category><category>Spring Roo</category><category>chariot-news</category><category>chariot-news</category><category>spring-roo</category><category>testing</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 14:18:59 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/7/8/spocks-data-tables-are-sweet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:17517883</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I'm working with Spock again for updating my CoffeeScript plugin for Roo 1.2.3.  There have been a few helpful additions to the add-on <span class="caps">API</span>s (unless I missed them in 1.2.2...) and so my code is getting a tad simpler.</p>

<p>The coolest thing is that converting my tests to Spock, I had an easy way to do a truth table testing condition when I wanted to try out a number of scenarios. Check out this snippet, specifically the "where:" block and the values from the where block variables within the test conditions.</p>

<p>I've switched this test to the more formal given: when: then: syntax, and added the where: section for the data tables settings. I think I was using setup: instead of given: and I also didn't put my expectations in the then: section, which they evaluate in regardless. It's more readable this way.</p>

<p><em>Note, the version of the coffeescript add-on listed in the test is irrelevant, as the method called to fetch the plugin ignores it but the Plugin constructor requires a version.</em></p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
@Unroll(&quot;evalto #evalto for project available #available, 
         packaging #packaging and pluginList #pluginList&quot;)
def &quot;test isPluginInstalled with scenarios&quot;() {
    given:
    def projectOperations = Mock(ProjectOperations.class)
    coffeescriptOperations.projectOperations = projectOperations
    def pom = Mock(Pom.class)

    when:
    def result = coffeescriptOperations.isPluginInstalled()

    then:
    coffeescriptOperations.projectOperations
            .isFocusedProjectAvailable() &gt;&gt; available
    coffeescriptOperations.projectOperations.getFocusedModule() &gt;&gt; pom
    pom.getPackaging() &gt;&gt; packaging
    pom.getBuildPluginsExcludingVersion(_) &gt;&gt; pluginList

    result == evalto

    where:
    pluginList | available | packaging  | evalto
    [] | false | &quot;foo&quot; | false
    [] | true  | &quot;war&quot; | false
    [] | true  | &quot;pom&quot; | false
    [new Plugin(&quot;com.theoryinpractise&quot;,
            &quot;coffee-maven-plugin&quot;, &quot;1.2.0&quot;) ] | true | &quot;war&quot; | true
    [new Plugin(&quot;com.theoryinpractise&quot;,
            &quot;coffee-maven-plugin&quot;, &quot;1.2.0&quot;)] | true | &quot;pom&quot; | false
}
</pre>



<p>I was able to fold five specific test cases checking whether the project contains the Coffeescript plugin into one test with five data settings (all false except one):</p>

<ul>
<li>The focused project is not available</li>
<li>The packaging is a war, the focused project is available, the add-on is not installed</li>
<li>The packaging is a "pom" and the project is available</li>
<li>The plugin exists, the type is a war, the focused module is available (happy!)</li>
<li>The plugin exists (mounted by hand perhaps) on a pom project which is the current module</li>
</ul>

<p>I used @Unroll to turn the data table results into five separate tests, each of which listed separately in the test results. Note the method name of the test is comprised of literal strings with data from the datatable columns starting with '#'. Nice, eh? </p>

<p>So I was able to collapse five test scenarios into one with the data tables. Nice.</p>

<p>You can pull the git repository for this add-on by using:</p>


<pre>
git clone git://git.cloudbees.com/sillyweasel/coffeescript-roo-addon.git
</pre>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-17517883.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Now on java.net : my article on WebFlow and Roo from the "Cutting Room Floor" of Roo in Action</title><category>SpringSource Roo</category><category>chariot-news</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 13:30:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/6/21/now-on-javanet-my-article-on-webflow-and-roo-from-the-cuttin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:16877553</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>You can read my first <a href="http://java.net">java.net</a> article, posted on our behalf from Manning's author articles series, entitled <a href="http://today.java.net/article/2012/06/19/spring-roo-and-webflow-ken-rimple-co-author-spring-roo-action?force=551" target="_blank">Spring Roo and WebFlow</a>, on Java.Net's technical articles series starting today.</p>

<p>Thanks to Manning's Nermina Miller for helping me get it finished, java.net's Kevin Farnham for publishing it, and Manning's Candace Gillhooley for getting the project going.</p>

<p>I anticipate a few more "cutting room floor" articles, since the book took some twisty turns while Srini and I were formulating the content for the final book.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-16877553.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spock and Roo - more complex mocks</title><category>Roo in Action</category><category>Spock</category><category>Spring Roo</category><category>roo add-ons</category><category>spring-roo</category><category>testing</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 04:19:35 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/5/25/spock-and-roo-more-complex-mocks.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:16436631</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Given this method to test:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
public boolean isInstalljQueryUICommandAvailable() {

  String jsLocation = pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(
      Path.SRC_MAIN_WEBAPP, &quot;/js&quot;);
  if (projectOperations.isFocusedProjectAvailable()) {
    boolean isMissingjQueryUI = fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
        jsLocation + &quot;/jquery-ui-*.min.js&quot;).isEmpty();
    return !isInstalljQueryCommandAvailable() &amp;&amp; isMissingjQueryUI;
  } else {
    return false;
  }
}
</pre>



<p>We have several challenges here:</p>

<ul>
<li>We are calling the <code>isInstalljQueryCommandAvailable()</code> method from my prior post, so we need to mock the code in that invocation</li>
<li>We are going to call the same methods with different results</li>
<li>We have to mock a non-empty call to the findMatchingAntPath</li>
</ul>

<p>To refer you to the prior method, here it is:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
public boolean isInstalljQueryCommandAvailable() {
  String jsLocation = pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(
      Path.SRC_MAIN_WEBAPP, &quot;/js&quot;);

  return fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
      jsLocation + &quot;**/jquery-1.*.min.js&quot;).isEmpty();
}
</pre>



<h3>Setting up our test mocks</h3>

<p>The test setup needs to take those conditions into account. First, we define our test method and fill in what we expect to happen:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
def &quot;isJqueryUIInstallAvailable called and happy path&quot;() {

     setup:

     when:
     def result = operations.isInstalljQueryUICommandAvailable()

     then:
     result == true
}
</pre>



<h3>The setup</h3>

<p>Ok, now let's define our setup block. We'll need to return a simulated search result for our invocation of the <code>pathResolver.findMatchingAntPath</code> method in the jquery availability check - we want to state that we already have jQuery, but not jQuery <span class="caps">UI, </span>in our search path. So, let's create a simulated file details object first:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
setup:
FileDetails fd = new FileDetails(new File(&quot;foo&quot;), 234L);
SortedSet&lt;FileDetails&gt; fileDetailsSet = new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;()
fileDetailsSet.add(fd)
</pre>



<p>Now, we'll start by defining our mock conditions for something where the return value won't vary: the getFocusedIdentifier method of the <code>pathResolver</code>. Because we're just mocking it anyway, we don't really care what we return. This is true in both cases where it is called. So, we'll just return a junk value, but do it twice so that we can expect it to be called two times, and return the same result:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
2* operations.pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(_, _) &gt;&gt; &quot;foo&quot;
</pre>



<p>So far, so good. Next, we'll mock a call to the <code>isFocusedProjectAvailable()</code> method of <code>projectOperations</code>. Hey, I noticed I do this in the UI setup, but not in the jQuery <span class="caps">API </span>setup, so I found a bug this way! So, it's two invocations, and I added the single invocation to the other test methods for the jQuery <span class="caps">API </span>setup too. Yay, team!:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
2* operations.projectOperations.isFocusedProjectAvailable() &gt;&gt; true
</pre>



<p>Next, the more difficult one. I want to make sure we find the jQuery <span class="caps">API</span> JS file in the search, but <span class="caps">NOT </span>the jQueryUI <span class="caps">API.</span> In other words, I want to make sure we have jQuery but <span class="caps">NOT </span>jQueryUI, so that we can then allow the user to install jQueryUI.</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
2* operations.fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(_) &gt;&gt;&gt;
                [new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;(), fileDetailsSet]
</pre>



<p>Wait, what? Ok, the syntax goes like this: we want two calls to the findMatchingAntPath method. The triple greater-than signs state that each invocation will return a different value. The first time, we'll return an empty TreeSet, which is the contract the method provides if no search result is found. The second time, we'll return a mocked set of file details, with our bogus one inside (we're then calling the one for jQuery, not jQueryUI, and we have to fake out that we have something.</p>

<p>The full test looks like this:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
def &quot;isJqueryUIInstallAvailable called and happy path&quot;() {

     setup:
     FileDetails fd = new FileDetails(new File(&quot;foo&quot;), 234L);
     SortedSet&lt;FileDetails&gt; fileDetailsSet = new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;()
     fileDetailsSet.add(fd)

     2* operations.pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(_, _) &gt;&gt; &quot;foo&quot;
     2* operations.projectOperations.isFocusedProjectAvailable() &gt;&gt; true
     2* operations.fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(_) &gt;&gt;&gt;
             [new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;(), fileDetailsSet]

     when:
     def result = operations.isInstalljQueryUICommandAvailable()

     then:
     result == true
}
</pre>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-16436631.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spock and Roo - Maven's conventions step in to mess with me</title><category>Spock</category><category>Spring Roo</category><category>maven</category><category>roo add-ons</category><category>spring-roo</category><category>testing</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 22:06:21 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/5/24/spock-and-roo-mavens-conventions-step-in-to-mess-with-me.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:16432370</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Ok, here's a cautionary tale.</p>

<p>I had everything working just fine in one project using Spock - on Jenkins builds I was getting code coverage working. It was great!</p>

<p>Hey, listen, keep this in mind:</p>

<p>src/test/java is <span class="caps">NOT </span>src/main/groovy! Now my jQuery project is <a href="https://sillyweasel.ci.cloudbees.com/job/jquery-roo-addon%20builder/14/cobertura/">starting to use code coverage</a> - go ahead and view the report...</p>

<p>Oh, and one more thing: bind them to test-compile, not test. <span class="caps">AAAHH</span>!</p>

<p>:)</p>

<p>Ok, here's my maven build fragment for running the tests (I assume now that the file set is no longer needed...)</p>



<pre class="brush: xml;">

&lt;plugin&gt;
    &lt;groupId&gt;org.codehaus.gmaven&lt;/groupId&gt;
    &lt;artifactId&gt;gmaven-plugin&lt;/artifactId&gt;
    &lt;version&gt;1.4&lt;/version&gt;
    &lt;configuration&gt;
        &lt;providerSelection&gt;1.8&lt;/providerSelection&gt;
    &lt;/configuration&gt;
    &lt;executions&gt;
        &lt;execution&gt;
			&lt;id&gt;test-run&lt;/id&gt;
            &lt;goals&gt;
				&lt;goal&gt;generateTestStubs&lt;/goal&gt;
                &lt;goal&gt;testCompile&lt;/goal&gt;
            &lt;/goals&gt;
			&lt;phase&gt;test-compile&lt;/phase&gt;
			&lt;configuration&gt;
				&lt;sources&gt;								
						&lt;fileSet&gt;
							&lt;directory&gt;src/test/groovy&lt;/directory&gt;
							&lt;includes&gt;
								&lt;include&gt;**/*.groovy&lt;/include&gt;
							&lt;/includes&gt;
						&lt;/fileSet&gt;							
				&lt;/sources&gt;
			&lt;/configuration&gt;						
        &lt;/execution&gt;
    &lt;/executions&gt;
    &lt;dependencies&gt;
        &lt;dependency&gt;
            &lt;groupId&gt;org.codehaus.gmaven.runtime&lt;/groupId&gt;
            &lt;artifactId&gt;gmaven-runtime-1.7&lt;/artifactId&gt;
            &lt;version&gt;1.3&lt;/version&gt;
            &lt;exclusions&gt;
                &lt;exclusion&gt;
                    &lt;groupId&gt;org.codehaus.groovy&lt;/groupId&gt;
                    &lt;artifactId&gt;groovy-all&lt;/artifactId&gt;
                &lt;/exclusion&gt;
            &lt;/exclusions&gt;
        &lt;/dependency&gt;
        &lt;dependency&gt;
            &lt;groupId&gt;org.codehaus.groovy&lt;/groupId&gt;
            &lt;artifactId&gt;groovy-all&lt;/artifactId&gt;
            &lt;version&gt;1.8.6&lt;/version&gt;
        &lt;/dependency&gt;
        &lt;dependency&gt;
            &lt;groupId&gt;org.spockframework&lt;/groupId&gt;
            &lt;artifactId&gt;spock-core&lt;/artifactId&gt;
            &lt;version&gt;0.6-groovy-1.8&lt;/version&gt;
        &lt;/dependency&gt;
        &lt;dependency&gt;
            &lt;groupId&gt;org.spockframework&lt;/groupId&gt;
            &lt;artifactId&gt;spock-spring&lt;/artifactId&gt;
            &lt;version&gt;0.6-groovy-1.8&lt;/version&gt;
        &lt;/dependency&gt;
    &lt;/dependencies&gt;
&lt;/plugin&gt;
</pre>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-16432370.xml</wfw:commentRss></item><item><title>Spock and Roo = easier add-on testing, part 2</title><category>Spring Roo</category><category>chariot-news</category><category>roo add-ons</category><category>spring-roo</category><dc:creator>Ken Rimple</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 10:30:24 +0000</pubDate><link>http://rimple.com/tech/2012/5/24/spock-and-roo-easier-add-on-testing-part-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">325483:3416732:16424671</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Moving on to some more interesting tests. Given this method:</p>



<pre class="brush: java;">

public boolean isInstalljQueryCommandAvailable() {
    String jsLocation = pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(
        Path.SRC_MAIN_WEBAPP, &quot;/js&quot;);

    return fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
        jsLocation + &quot;**/jquery-1.*.min.js&quot;).isEmpty();
  }
</pre>



<p>I want to use Spock to test it. The challenge is the somewhat more nested set of objects. My add-on extends the AbstractOperations class (to get the embedded <code>fileManager</code>), so I need to mock that, plus mock the path resolver I've mounted with <code>@Reference</code> in my add-on as well.</p>

<p>To set it up I do this:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
class JqueryuiOperationsImplTest extends spock.lang.Specification {

    JqueryuiOperationsImpl operations;

    def setup() {
        operations = new JqueryuiOperationsImpl();

        operations.pathResolver = Mock(PathResolver);
        operations.fileManager = Mock(FileManager);
    }

</pre>



<p>Spock mocks are similar to EasyMock, in that we then detail our assertions of what should happen before the test runs. In fact, based on a <a href="https://groups.google.com/group/spockframework/browse_frm/thread/8c364dd63b2e359b">really interesting thread</a> I found this AM while banging my head against the wall (don't do that, it hurts), if you put any mocking assertions in the when: part of a Spock test, it moves them to the setup: block. Anyway, here is my set of assertions:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
    def &quot;isJqueryInstallAvailable called and happy path&quot;() {

        setup:
        1* operations.pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(
                _, _) &gt;&gt; &quot;src/main/webapp/js&quot;

        1* operations.fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
                _ as String) &gt;&gt; new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;()

</pre>



<p>I'm using Spock's matchers to eat the expressions - I don't really care what we pass to the <code>getFocusedIdentifier</code> or <code>findMatchingAntPath</code> methods, I just want them mocked and I want them to return values. </p>

<p>The &gt;&gt; is what tells us that we're stubbing the return output. </p>

<p>Here is the full test:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">
    def &quot;isJqueryInstallAvailable called and happy path&quot;() {
        setup:
        1* operations.pathResolver.getFocusedIdentifier(
                _, _) &gt;&gt; &quot;src/main/webapp/js&quot;

        1* operations.fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
                _ as String) &gt;&gt; new TreeSet&lt;FileDetails&gt;()

        when:
        def result = operations.isInstalljQueryCommandAvailable();

        then:
        result == true
    }
</pre>



<p>Don't do what I did to get my head bruised. I originally wrote this:</p>



<pre class="brush: groovy;">

1* operations.fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
                _ as String).empty() &gt;&gt; false
</pre>



<p>I got my brain mixed up because I saw the line:</p>



<pre class="brush: java;">
    return fileManager.findMatchingAntPath(
        jsLocation + &quot;**/jquery-1.*.min.js&quot;).isEmpty();
</pre>



<p>And that's going to throw a tasty NullPointerException because you're mocking the return <strong>of the method in fileManager</strong>, not the return statement! Oh, bother.</p>
]]></description><wfw:commentRss>http://rimple.com/tech/rss-comments-entry-16424671.xml</wfw:commentRss></item></channel></rss>